if you've been considering relocating to
the central Texas area particularly
Temple or belon and you're curious what
our luxury Market looks like you'll want
to watch this video today because I will
be taking you on a tour of three
stunning luxury resale homes in belon
Texas we'll be comparing different price
points features locations and so whether
you're looking for something classic um
modern or truly high-end you get a great
feel of what's available in our Market
hello and welcome to living in Central
Texas belon is one of the most sought
after areas in Central Texas offering
lake views top rated schools and that
perfect mix of small town charm and
luxury living so stick around and let's
dive in so what is luxury real estate
luxury real estate is about double
whatever the average price point is for
a particular area yes so in Bell County
or in the temple Bell area our average
price point is just under 300,000 so I
would say luxury is going to be be
considered anything over that 500,000
close to 600,000 price point so if I
search
here just active homes in belon Texas
212 homes pop up just in belon we could
expand that a little bit if we wanted to
because there are some homes within
Temple that fall in Bel and ISD so if
it's just a school district that you're
interested in that's more important to
you you'll want to make sure that you
have an
agent um search that way so for example
I can search by School District belon
ISD and we get 447 homes much much
larger so if we search within Belton ISD
homes over 550,000
68 homes populate so you can see how
that number really shrink down and if we
go to the map this is a map of you have
Temple right here you have Temple here
you have belt in here but there's a lot
of overlap so you can be within Temple
and even this is part of Temple oddly
and you still be within belt and
ISD so we're just going to be searching
Bel and ISD and I picked three homes for
us to tour today so we will be focusing
on these three homes marked here this is
going to give you a really great idea of
very different areas in belon and what
the houses look like and what you get
for that so I thought this was really
fun I am so excited to show you these
homes um so without further Ado let's
get started
so our first stop today is in the
community of river place this is a more
established Community but the homes are
really beautiful on really great sized
Lots it's got mature
landscaping and the location is really
ideal um in terms of proximity to
everything so you're very centrally
located in belon it's belon ISD right
off of Lake Road and you have shopping
just minutes away you're probably 2
minutes away from HB some really great
restaurants um you're four to 5 minutes
away from Belton Lake and just a really
great option all around if you're
looking for luxury in belon this home
was built in 2002 it's priced at
799,000
so much space there's five bed
four
bath it's on an 1 acre lot some really
cool features are it has a built-in pool
and a mother-in-law Suite it has three
car attached garage and twocc car
detached garage so the outside of the
home has brick it's foursided brick you
have gutters around and as you can tell
really big beautiful trees but as you
walk into the home technically this is a
two-story house but most of the living
space is downstairs walk in here we have
your office space with some vinyl plank
flooring super tall ceilings throughout
the
home crown molding throughout the paint
is kind of like an off-white I think
some paint and new carpet would really
transform this house
here you have your formal dining
space this Loops into the kitchen you
have granite
countertops Custom Cabinets double oven
and then it opens up into your living
space within the kitchen there's um an
eat in kitchen in the living space they
really like their chandeliers there's a
lot of chandeliers in this
house you have a gas fireplace I guess
this would be a flex room I was trying
to guess what you might use the space
for cuz you have that formal dining
space up front across from the office it
connects over to the I guess pool house
attached pool
house summer pool days here in Texas
being able to open up these doors have
people come in and out to
swim use the kitchen grill burgers hot
dogs this is not a super open concept
floor plan and so if you like things a
little more
segmented um this might be the house for
you and this is your mother-in-law Suite
so it's offset from the rest of the
house you have your master on the other
side split floor plan then the
Mother-in-law Suite you have your own
vanities tub shower
combo down here you have have your two
other
bedrooms and another full
bath okay so here we're going to head on
up to the loft all right as we come
upstairs you have a really decent sized
Loft area with a full bath
a little closet area additional storage
got your HVAC unit in
here and then you have that fifth
bedroom right off the Loft
area and then over here off the kitchen
you have your laundry
room with a nice little built-in utility
sink tons of storage and space in
here and then within the master you have
some tray ceilings crown molding
additional recess lighting cute little
built-in
bookshelf and then the primary bath has
nice jetted tub walk-in shower and dual
vanities separate closed off
commode a lot of closet space
you step outside you have a very
beautiful pool and hot tub which looks
like it needs to be maybe worked on a
tiny bit and filled up and replenished
but this is nice and fenced off from the
rest of your yard again really great
size 1 acre lot it has a detached
shed and then your two-car garage so for
our second luxury stop of the day in Bel
in Texas we are in a very beautiful home
in the escarment subdivision this is
more
Southwest belon actually very close to
Nolanville it's really between belon
Nolanville um pretty close to C Texas as
well more private I think than our first
house um much larger lot but much more
secluded so you do get that in tradeoff
for being as close to all of the
amenities in our last house in
Riverplace that one was again minutes
just right up the street from shop
um but this one you're probably 12 to 15
minutes either to belon or Harker
Heights for your shopping it is a four
bed 4 and a half bath home um over 4,000
square ft built in 2004 on just over 2
Acres so you can see it's very Regal out
front you have this beautiful um outdoor
fountain a portico the entire front of
the property is fenced in you have a
really great security feature at the
front of the property with a rod iron
electric gate and then right off the
Circle Drive here you have a drive to
your detached
garage and then as we finish off this
home we'll also check out this home's
pool and kind of compare this pool and
spa to the last um and just see what
this price difference really gets to you
while our last one was priced just under
seven this one is at 1.3 good comparison
of differences in luxury in our area
let's go as we enter the home it has an
incredibly Grand
foyer incredibly tall ceilings and a
spiral staircase leading
upstairs you have these um concrete
columns accented throughout the exterior
and
interior Venetian Plastering on the wall
which is this funky style of painting
this is just a sitting area I guess a
second living space wood burning
fireplace just off the entry you also
have your formal dining space some
really pretty accents on the wall with
your um chair rail and then this is
going to loop around to the living space
and kitchen here you have a Butler's
Pantry which is also a bar
area welcome to your Gourmet
Kitchen this is a very well designed and
well laid out kitchen you have
commercial grade appliances throughout
eight burner gas wolf
range really large and oversized prep
Island and your larger oversized kitchen
sink here which is really great because
because you can do
dishes talk with family and just get the
most beautiful view while you do dishes
like no one enjoys doing just off the
kitchen is your laundry room/ utility
room this is your more formal um living
room you have those really nice built-in
bookshelves on both sides of the
fireplace Eden kitchen which you can
really just imagine having coffee um
eating breakfast
and enjoying that view these are
incredibly High ceilings because of that
two story makes it feel very bright open
in here downstairs we have one bedroom
this is more of a mother-in-law sweet
style but very generous sized guest
bedroom private patio
access and then a very
nice bathroom
with a walk-in
shower so in comparison to the last
house we looked at these are very
comparable in a lot of ways in terms of
size I mean they're both over that 4,000
square foot Mark um very different in
the design very different in the
location um and I feel that this one has
obviously more upgraded features and
what really sells this home is its
privacy seclusion and that view I mean
that is a very one-of-a-kind view for
this area something else that's really
unique to this house is that every
single bedroom has its own bathrooms
we're just going to do a quick look in
this one the lights aren't working so
it's a little dark and jury interesting
wood Accent on the
wall smaller sized bathroom but added-on
bathroom nonetheless toilet sink and
shower tub
combo you have two stair accesses one
off the entryway from the foyer and the
second off of the kitchen we are inside
the primary bedroom hardwood flooring
throughout and check out this
closet so huge never run out of space in
here lots of storage for all your shoes
and then inside the primary Suite take a
look
now part of that
$1.3
million is this
F this extended patio also connects to
one of the other guest
bedrooms this is our fourth and final
bedroom with its own separate bathroom
little bit different up here a little
bit larger tile granite countertops
Custom
Cabinets and walk-in
shower and of course its own private
access to the patio with its own
beautiful view step outside to our
backyard of our $1.3 million luxury
listing in belon
Texas you have two separate seating
areas two separate covered patio area
entertaining some fenced in yard up here
a gas fireplace you have your spa and
you have your hot tub and pool
overlooking the beautiful Lake once
again some other neat features are the
gener as well as the 900 squ ft detached
garage which is also heated and
insulated I'm curious to hear what your
thoughts are comparing this 1.3 luxury
listing to the $799 luxury listing that
we just looked at do you think this view
is worth that difference our third and
final stop is in Honey Glenn acres in
belon Texas also in belon ISD this
location is totally different it is more
Southeast belon closer to Little River
Academy and Temple on the east side of
I35 so this home was built in in 2021
it's about 3500 Square ft it's listed as
a five bed 4 and a half bath it's really
A four bed four and a half bath with an
upstairs Loft um really good use of
space if you like open Concepts more
modern design this is probably the house
for you the outside of this home is with
a hearty Plank and brick mixture really
pretty and elegant let's see what $1.3
million buys you in Honey Glen Acres in
belon
Texas welcome to home number three since
this home is much newer it is much more
updated much more modern and it's really
open and
beautiful so when we walk in you have
your main living space and this
beautiful floor to ceiling stone
fireplace wood burning it Blends very
nicely into your dining space
overlooking your wonderful backyard
you'll also love the amazing vaulted
ceilings with wood
beams recess lighting it just feels
incredibly open and bright in this space
even though it's a very gloomy
day kitchen again very open concept chef
kitchen with this awesome oversized
granite countertop in the center they
have the golden black selections
throughout with accent Ed black
Hardware you have a wonderful gas range
this is a split floor plan and
surprisingly it's a two-story it doesn't
really look that way to me out front but
it
is majority of your rooms being
downstairs this is one of the guest
bedrooms you have that luxury vinyl
plank throughout here as well good size
walk-in closet this this room faces the
street and then you have your attached
bathroom fully tiled walk-in
shower so this is the primary bedroom
with the accent walls they went with a
peor in this room whereas the other
walls throughout the home are just
white recessed lighting in
[Music]
here does feel very bright and they have
this awesome mirrored barn door that
leads you into your primary
bathroom separate commode that's nice
for privacy center of the master bath is
going to be or the primary bath is going
to be that soaking tub dual vanity
really pretty gold mirrors and um accent
pendants love this walk-in shower
there's also a seating
area for you to sit or shave your legs
there are two closets
so you can have separate
spaces good amount of storage in here
this is a much newer Community you know
the last house that we were looking at
was more lake property this is more Farm
property you can actually see when we go
in the backyard you're overlooking farms
and horses and it's crazy how you're
really not that far from the last house
but you definitely feel like you're in a
different area just off the kitchen I
think they made a good use of space here
just under the
stairs semi Harry Potter feel you have
built-in bookshelves little built-in
desk you have two more bedrooms here
with a Jack and Jill bathroom I really
love that
feature again no carpet they did some
funky tile in here which I
like got some blue Accents in there
whereas they went with the gold hardware
and the master the hardware and mirrors
and pendants or um Lighting in here is
all black
accented good walk-in closets in all the
guest bedrooms so they're counting this
Loft space as a
bedroom I don't see a closet so I guess
technically it's not but you could use
this as an additional bedroom if you'd
like Flex
space play area
just really good use of space cute
little nook if you want to put some
pillows make it a reading Nook and it
overlooks your awesome basketball court
volleyball court pickleball court
whatever you want that Court to be I
suppose and then inside this store is
your attic
space which is
floored for great additional storage
just off the kitchen you have your
Butler's Pantry which is phenomenal it
has a builtin
stove sink additional
cabinets counter space your laundry
space here again another sink some funky
hexagon
tile as you come in through the garage
this is your two-car garage you also
have that detached garage you have a mud
bench with hooks so you can drop all of
your stuff here across from your laundry
room so dirty kids spouses whatever can
strip down and throw everything in the
laundry
room just off the kitchen hole you have
that extra half bath for
guests step outside to this awesome
backyard right when you step outside
you'll notice this awesome covered patio
and builtin kitchen out um your outdoor
barbecue kitchen Area Pool Spa and a
fire
feature there are no privacy fences here
which I guess take it or leave it but
this overlooks the farm area pasture
lands so really pretty view behind you
so just off of the pool in the backyard
you have your Cabana which could be dual
purposed as a home gym yoga studio
whatever you'd like because it also has
a full bathroom with a
shower thank you so much for touring
this these three beautiful luxury
listings in belon Texas today I hope you
found it useful if you'd like to see
some luxury new construction I'll be
sure to do a video on that here soon so
don't forget to subscribe to my channel
like this video and click the Bell icon
so that you can stay up toate on all
things real estate here in Central Texas
till next time